Marcel Breuer
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Project Files, 1921-1986, Series 8:; (Boxes 8-23, 36-40, OVs 43-57; Reels 5720-5737; 27.6 linear feet)
  - Urban Development Projects, 1928-1981, 8.1:
    - Boston Redevelopment Parcel 8 Competition, Boston, Massachusetts, 1964 (Box 8, Reel 5720, Frame 223-227)
      (letters from Breuer to Sverud Associates and Jaros Baum & Bolles)
    - Potsdamer Platz, Berlin, Germany, 1928-1929 (Box 8, Reel 5720, Frame 228-237)
      (photographs of plans for traffic clover-leaf pattern for a multi-level traffic circulation system)
    - Sadat City Ministries Complex, Cairo, Egypt, 1976-1981, (oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 8, Reel 5720, Frame 238-254)
    - South Boston Redevelopment Project, Boston, Massachusetts, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Reel 5720, Frame 255-262)
    - Stuyvesant Six (housing development), New York, New York, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Reel 5720, Frame 263-273)
    - Oversized Sadat City Ministries Complex, Cairo, Egypt, 1976-1981, (oversized material scanned with Box 8, Reel 5720, Frames 238-254) (Box 36, Reel 5720)
  - Planned Communities, 1928-1976, 8.2:
    This subseries consists of 10 project files concerning the construction of facilities for specific communities.
    The subseries is arranged alphabetically by project.
    - Acquitaine Coast Resort, Port Contis, France, 1971-1973, 8.2.1:
      - Letters and contract (Box 8, Reel 5720, Frame 276-299)
      - Photographs of a map and drawings, (oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 8, Reel 5720, Frame 300-318)
      - Negatives (Box 8, Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
      - Oversized photographs of a map and drawings, (oversized material scanned with Box 8, Reel 5720, Frames 300-318) (Box 36, Reel 5720)
    - El Recreo Urban Center, Caracas, Venezuela, 1958-1960, 8.2.2:
      - Letters (Box 8, Reel 5720, Frame 320-327)
      - Photographs of plans, drawings, and model, (3 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5720, Frame 328-366)
      - Negatives, (2 folders) (Box 8, Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
      - Clippings (Box 8, Reel 5720, Frame 367-399)
    - Flaine Ski Resort Town, Haute-Savoie, France, 1960-1976, 8.2.3:
      - Letters and contracts (Box 8, Reel 5720, Frame 401-449)
      - Photographs of Breuer and Eric Boissonnas; photographs of plans, (4 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5720, Frame 450-506)
      - Photographs of drawings, (oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 8, Reel 5720, Frame 507-517)
      - Photographs of model, (oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 8, Reel 5720, Frame 518-534)
      - Photographs of construction and completed project, exterior, (26 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5720, Frame 535-687)
      - Photographs of construction and completed project, exterior, (26 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 688-883)
      - Photographs of completed project, interior, (3 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 884-925)
      - Negatives, (7 folders) (Box 9, Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
      - Color transparencies, (2 folders) (Box 9, Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
      - Clippings and booklet, (oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 926-1024)
      - Oversized photographs of drawings, (oversized material scanned with Box 8, Reel 5720, Frame 507-517) (Box 36, Reel 5720)
      - Oversized photographs of model, (oversized material scanned with Box 8, Reel 5720, Frames 518-534) (Box 36, Reel 5720)
      - Oversized clippings and booklet, (oversized material scanned with Box 9, Reel 5720, Frames 926-1024) (Box 36, Reel 5720)
    - Interama (Community for Argentina, Brazil, Paraguay, and Uruguay), Miami, Florida, 1965-1967, 8.2.4:
      - Letters and contract (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 1026-1040)
      - Transcript of a press conference (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 1041-1056)
      - Press release and booklets (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 1057-1094)
      - Photographs of architects (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 1095-1096)
        (Breuer, Edward Durell Stone, José Luis Sert, Louis I. Kahn, and Robert B. Browne with Irving E. Muskat, chairman of Interama, Harry M. Weese, and Paul Rudolph)
      - Aerial site photographs; photographs of plans (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 1097-1099)
      - Photographs of plans, drawings, model (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 1100-1134)
      - Negatives (Box 9, Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
      - Clippings (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 1135-1156)
    - Lawton Community, Lawton, Oklahoma, Letters and Contract, 1975-1976, 8.2.5:
      - Letters and Contract (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 1157-1202)
    - New Kensington Defense Housing, New Kensington, Pennsylvania, 1941, 8.2.6:
      - Photographs of plans, drawings, and model, (oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 1205-1222)
      - Photographs of construction (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 1223-1225)
      - Photographs of completed project, (6 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 1226-1247)
      - Negatives (Box 9, Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
      - Oversized photographs of plans, drawings, and model, (oversized material scanned with Box 9, Reel 5720, Frames 1205-1222) (Box 36, Reel 5720)
    - Spandau-Haselhorst Housing, Spandau, Germany, 1928, 8.2.7:
      - Photographs of plans and drawings (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 1248-1254)
    - Sports Park, Corona-Flushing Meadow Park, Queens, New York, 1966-1974, 8.2.8:
      - Letters and contracts (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 1256-1324)
      - Photographs of architects Breuer, Arthur Rosenblatt, and Lawrence Halprin (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 1325-1326)
      - Photographs of plans and drawings (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 1327-1332)
      - Photographs of model, (5 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5720, Frame 1333-1375)
      - Photographs of model, continued (Box 9, Reel 5721, Frame 12-19)
      - Negatives (Box 9, Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
      - Clippings (Box 9, Reel 5721, Frame 20-57)
    - Wellfleet Housing Development, Bi-Nuclear "H" House, Wellfleet, Massachusetts, 1943, 8.2.9:
      - Photographs of plans (Box 9, Reel 5721, Frame 58-62)
    - ZUP (Zone à Urbaniser par Priorité/"Zone Designated for Priority Urbanization"), Community Bayonne, France, 1964-1972, 8.2.10:
      - Letters and contracts (Box 9, Reel 5721, Frame 64-152)
      - Photographs of plans, (3 folders; oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 9, Reel 5721, Frame 153-179)
      - Photographs of drawings, (oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 9, Reel 5721, Frame 180-186)
      - Photographs of model and construction (Box 9, Reel 5721, Frame 187-198)
      - Photographs of completed project, (8 folders; oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 10, Reel 5721, Frame 199-248)
      - Negatives, (2 folders) (Box 10, Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
      - Clippings (Box 10, Reel 5721, Frame 249-261)
      - Oversized photographs of plans, (oversized material scanned with Box 9, Reel 5721, Frames 153-179) (Box 36, Reel 5721)
      - Oversized photographs of drawings, (oversized material scanned with Box 9, Reel 5721, Frames 180-186) (Box 36, Reel 5721)
      - Oversized photographs of completed project, (oversized material scanned with Box 36, Reel 5721, Frames 199-248) (Box 36, Reel 5721)
  - Government Agencies, 1949-1980, 8.3:
    This subseries consists of 6 project files concerning the construction of buildings for the U.S. government or for the governments of other countries. The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Australian Embassy, Paris, France, 1970-1976, 8.3.1:
      - Letters, notes, and contract, (3 folders) (Box 10, Reel 5721, Frame 264-349)
      - Photographs of plans, drawings, and model, (oversized material housed in Box 36 ) (Box 10, Reel 5721, Frame 350-397)
      - Photographs of architects Breuer, Harry Seidler, and Mario Jossa on the construction site; photographs of completed project, exterior (Box 10, Reel 5721, Frame 398-399)
      - Photographs of completed project, exterior (Box 10, Reel 5721, Frame 400-423)
      - Photographs of completed project, interior (Box 10, Reel 5721, Frame 424-427)
      - Negatives (Box 10, Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
      - Color transparencies (Box 10, Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
      - Clippings (Box 10, Reel 5721, Frame 428-439)
      - Oversized photographs of plans, drawings, and model, (oversized material scanned with Box 10, Reel 5721, Frames 350-397) (Box 36, Reel 5721)
    - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (HEW) Headquarters Building, Hubert H. Humphrey Building, "Air Rights Building-South Portal Site," Washington, D.C., 1965-1979, 8.3.2:
      - Letters, contracts, and blueprint, (10 folders) (Box 10, Reel 5721, Frame 441-912)
      - Photographs of plans, (5 folders) (Box 10, Reel 5721, Frame 913-938)
      - Photographs of drawings (Box 10, Reel 5721, Frame 939-947)
      - Photographs of model (Box 10, Reel 5721, Frame 948-954)
      - Photographs of construction (Box 10, Reel 5721, Frame 955-961)
      - Photographs of completed project, exterior, including photos by Herbert Beckhard, (8 folders; oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 10, Reel 5721, Frame 962-1020)
      - Photographs of completed project, interior, (3 folders; oversized material housed with Box 36) (Box 10, Reel 5721, Frame 1021-1047)
      - Negatives, (2 folders) (Box 10, Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
      - Color transparencies, (5 folders) (Box 10, Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
      - Printed material concerning the dedication and clippings (Box 10, Reel 5721, Frame 1048-1111)
      - Oversized photographs of completed project, exterior, including photos by Herbert Beckhard, (oversized material scanned with Box 10, Reel 5721, Frames 962-1020) (Box 36, Reel 5721)
      - Oversized Photographs of completed project, interior, (oversized material scanned with Box 10, Reel 5721, Frames 1021-1047) (Box 36, Reel 5721)
    - Department of Highways and Traffic, Headquarters Building Washington, D.C., 8.3.3:
      - Letters and contract, (4 folders) (Box OV 48, Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
    - Department of Housing and Urban Development(HUD), Headquarters Building Washington, D.C., 1963-1974, 8.3.4:
      - Letters and contract, (4 folders) (Box 11, Reel 5721, Frame 1114-1224)
      - Material concerning the investigation of the settling of the building, (4 folders) (Box 11, Reel 5721, Frame 1225-1366)
      - Photographs of plans, (2 folders) (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 12-28)
      - Photograph of drawing (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 29-31)
      - Photographs of completed project, exterior, (6 folders; oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 32-79)
      - Photographs of completed project, interior and dedication ceremony (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 80-86)
        (includes photos of President Lyndon and Mrs. Johnson)
      - Negatives, (2 folders) (Box 11, Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
      - Color transparencies (Box 11, Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
      - Clippings, (6 folders) (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 87-244)
      - Press releases (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 245-270)
      - Brochures and Miscellaneous Printed Material (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 271-330)
      - Oversized photographs of completed project, exterior, (oversized material scanned with Box 11, Reel 5722, Frames 32-79) (Box 36, Reel 5722)
    - Strom Thurmond Courthouse and Federal Office Building, Columbia, South Carolina, 1974-1980, 8.3.5:
      - Letters and printed "scope of services" instructions, (4 folders) (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 332-513)
      - Photographs of plans, drawing and model, (oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 514-539)
      - Contact sheet photographs of completed project, exterior and interior (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 540-557)
      - Photographs of completed project, exterior, (4 folders) (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 558-594)
      - Photographs of completed project, interior, (2 folders) (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 595-610)
      - Negatives and color transparencies (Box 11, Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
      - Oversized photographs of plans, drawing and model, (oversized material scanned with Box 11, Reel 5722, Frames 514-539) (Box 36, Reel 5722)
    - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) Headquarters, Paris, France, 1949-1975, 8.3.6:
      See Index B for an alphabetical listing of Breuer's chronologically arranged correspondence in this project file.
      Index B: Alphabetical List of Correspondents in 8.3.5: United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) Headquarters, Paris, France, 1949-1975
      Abramski, B. (Public Liaison Division, UNESCO), 1960 (1 letter)
      Adams, Faneuil (Hill, Barlow, Goodale & Wiswall), 1952 (1 letter)
      Addison Gallery of American Art (Bartlett Hayes), 1953 (1 letter)
      Aicardi, Simone (Law Offices of S. G. Archibald), 1967-1971 (4 letters)
      Architectural Review (J. M. Richards), 1952 (2 letters)
      Architecture 52 (Frederique Seger), 1953 (1 letter)
      Arnaud, Leopold (Columbia University), 1952 (1 letter)
      Association du Personnel, UNESCO Staff Association (R. Schaufelberger), 1953-1954 (2 letters)
      Bliss, Anthony A., 1953 (1 letter): from Bliss' office
      Bodet, Jaime Torres (director general of UNESCO), 1952 (1 letter)
      Bogner, Walter F. (architect), 1952 (1 letter)
      Borglum, Paul, 1953 (1 letter)
      Brewer, Charles D., 1952 (1 letter)
      Brugere, Lucien, 1959 (1 letter)
      Cabouat, J. P. (Permanent French Delegation Attached to UNESCO), 1957 (1 letter): from M. Montagnier
      Callison, Eugène H. (chief engineer), 1956-1958 (94 letters) Carter, Edward (librarian, UNESCO), 1954 (1 letter): from Walter Gropius
      Cement and Concrete Association (Philip Gooding), 1954 (1 letter)
      Clark, Dallas (Mrs. Donald N. Clark), 1952 (1 letter)
      Corbin Lock Division (Rudolf Zelinka), 1957 (1 letter)
      Costa, Lucio (architect), 1952-1953 (1 telegram, 1 letter): telegram from Breuer; 1953 letter dictated by Walter Gropius to Howard Robertson with lines for signatures of Costa, Gropius, Sven Markelius, and Ernesto Rogers
      Dezell, Mr. (Building Management, UNESCO), 1956 (1 letter): from W. Mactaggart
      d'Harnoncourt, René (Museum of Modern Art), 1957 (2 letters)
      d'Hennezel, Mourer, 1953 (1 letter)
      Duprat, Mr., 1961 (1 letter): from Bernard Zehrfuss
      Edwards, David J. (Georgia Institute of Technology), 1952 (1 letter)
      Ehrmann, Gilles, 1959 (1 telegram): from Breuer
      Eken, Andrew J. (Starrett Brothers and Eken), 1952-1953 (2 letters)
      Emslie, Murray Sims, 1958 (1 letter)
      Evans, Luther H. (director general), 1955-1959 (6 letters)
      Evarts, John, undated (1 calling card)
      Foster, Richard, 1957 (1 letter)
      Fry, Lynn W. (University of Michigan, Ann Arbor), 1953 (1 letter)
      Fulchignoni, Enrico (head of the film department), 1957 (1 letter): to Eugène Callison
      Gatje, Robert Frederick, 1967 (1 letter)
      Gazette de Lausanne, 1958 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
      Goodwin, Philip L. (architect), 1952-1953 (2 letters)
      Goss, Dale (Seattle Public Schools), 1953 (1 letter)
      Graber, Rudolf (Wohnbedarf furniture store), 1957 (1 letter): from Breuer, includes a photograph of interior of a cafeteria
      Gropius, Walter and Ise, 1952-1961 (63 letters): 30 from Breuer
      Grossi, Olindo (Pratt Institute), 1952 (1 letter)
      Hansen, J. Dilling, 1960 (9 letters)
      Harper-Smith, Mr., 1958 (1 letter): from Bernard Zehrfuss
      Harvard University, 1952 (1 letter): from President Conant's office
      Hauf, Harold D. (Edwards Street Laboratory), 1952 (1 letter)
      Hervé, Lucien (photographer), 1957 (1 letter)
      Hill, Henry, 1952 (1 letter)
      Julius Hoffmann Verlag Stuttgart, 1955-1956 (4 letters)
      Hopkins, Frank S. (UNESCO Relations Staff), 1957 (1 letter)
      Hutchins, John Jay (Law Offices of S. G. Archibald), 1967-1975 (34 letters): 16 from Breuer
      Institute of Contemporary Art, 1952-1953 (2 letters)
      Jalles, Louis, 1967 (1 letter): to Bernard Zehrfuss)
      Johnson, Philip C., 1952-1963 (4 letters)
      Jours de France, 1958 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
      Kammerer, Struve (Akustisches Gutachten), 1959 (1 letter)
      Kaufman, Stanley Lloyd, 1953 (1 letter)
      Knoll, Hans G., 1953-1957 (2 letters)
      König, Max (Wohnbedarf furniture store), 1956 (1 letter)
      Large, R. A., 1952 (1 letter)
      La Rochelle, J. Drieu (wrote a report on ventilation with Zehrfuss), 1949
      Le Corbusier, 1952-1953 (8 letters): 2 to Walter Gropius; 2 to José Luis Sert
      Le Génie Civil, 1958 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
      Leguen, Yves, 1958-1960 (3 letters)
      Lewis, George Sherman (architect), 1952 (1 letter)
      Loeb, G. M. (E. F. Hutton & Company), 1952-1953 (2 letters)
      Lurie, H. Lee (Barron, Rice & Rockmore), 1952 (1 letter)
      Mactaggart, W. (DAO, UNESCO), 1956 (1 letter)
      Malecki, T., 1958 (1 letter)
      Mandleur et Dolbeau, 1957 (1 letter)
      Marcel, Pierre, 1957-1958 (58 letters): 24 from Breuer
      Markelius, Sven, 1953 (1 letter): dictated by Walter Gropius to Howard Robertson with lines for signatures of Lucio Costa, Gropius, Markelius, and Ernesto Rogers)
      McCray, Porter (Museum of Modern Art), 1957 (1 letter)
      McFadden, William Parker, undated (1 note of address)
      McMullough, Max, undated (1 calling card)
      Mérédieu, Denise, 1957-1959 (29 letters): 11 from Breuer
      Millquist, Jerome, 1955 (2 letters)
      Mohrhardt, Charles M. (Detroit Public Library), 1953 (1 letter)
      Montagnier, M. (head of the Office of Conferences and General Services), 1957-1961 (7 letters)
      Nervi, Pier Luigi, 1952-1975 (82 letters): 32 from Breuer
      New York Herald Tribune, 1952 (1 letter): from Breuer
      Osmun, Edward (New York Port Authority), 1962 (1 letter): from Breuer
      Perrault, Mr., 1961 (1 letter): from Breuer
      Pilzer, Leopold, 1952-1953 (2 letters)
      Présentè, G. M., 1958 (1 letter): from Bernard Zehrfuss
      Rawlings, Boynton M. (Law Offices of S. G. Archibald), 1967 (2 letters)
      Ritchie, Raymond D. (Ritchie Construction Company, Inc.), 1952 (1 letter)
      Robertson, Howard (Easton & Robertson, London), 1952-1953 (2 letters): 1 from Eero Saarinen; 1953 letter dictated by Walter Gropius to Robertson with lines for signatures of Lucio Costa, Gropius, Sven Markelius, and Ernesto Rogers
      Rocourt, Evelyn, 1954 (1 letter): see Project File for UNESCO
      Rogers, Ernesto N., 1953 (1 letter): dictated by Walter Gropius to Howard Robertson with lines for signatures of Lucio Costa, Gropius, Sven Markelius, and Rogers
      Roux, Alina, 1959 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
      Saarinen, Eero, 1952 (2 letters)
      Sert, José Luis (International Congresses for Modern Architecture, CIAM), 1952-1953 (7 letters)
      Smith, Hamilton, 1963 (1 letter)
      Stillman, Rufus and Leslie, 1958 (1 letter)
      Suter-Moser, Claude, 1955 (1 letter)
      Sutnar, Ladislav, 1956 (1 letter)
      George J. Switzer Company (Edmund Switzer), 1952 (1 letter)
      Székely, Tamás István (Wohnbedarf furniture store), 1957 (1 letter)
      Taylor, John W. (acting director general, UNESCO), 1953 (1 letter): from Walter Gropius
      Thomas, Jean (assistant director general), 1958 (7 letters)
      Thompson, Marion Gordon, 1953 (1 letter)
      Urlik, J. P. (secretary, UNESCO), 1958 (2 letters)
      Veronese, Vittorino (director general), 1959-1960 (5 letters)
      Vieco, Hernan, 1957-1958 (10 letters)
      Weidlinger, Paul, 1958 (1 letter)
      Wermeil, Benjamin, 1952 (6 letters): 5 from Breuer; 1 from Le Corbusier
      Wilkinson, J. R. (Stevens & Wilkinson), 1952 (1 letter)
      Zehrfuss, Bernard and Simone, undated and 1949-1967 (229 letters): 92 from Breuer
      - Contracts and supporting material, 1953-1957, (3 folders) (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 612-818)
      - Chronological correspondence, 1952, undated (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 819-927)
      - Chronological correspondence, 1953 (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 928-1013)
      - Chronological correspondence, 1954 (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 1014-1053)
      - Chronological correspondence, 1955 (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 1054-1087)
      - Chronological correspondence, 1956 (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 1088-1101)
      - Chronological correspondence, January 1957 (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 1102-1211)
      - Chronological correspondence, February 1957 (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 1212-1279)
      - Chronological correspondence, March-August 1957 (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 1280-1361)
      - Chronological correspondence, September-October 1957 (Box 11, Reel 5722, Frame 1362-1405)
      - Chronological correspondence, October-December 1957 (Box 11, Reel 5723, Frame 13-47)
      - Chronological correspondence, January-June 1958 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 48-127)
      - Chronological correspondence, July-December 1958 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 128-251)
      - Chronological correspondence, January-April 1959 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 252-341)
      - Chronological correspondence, May-December 1959 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 342-360)
      - Chronological correspondence, 1960 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 361-436)
      - Chronological correspondence, January-June 1961 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 437-533)
      - Chronological correspondence, July-December 1961 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 534-576)
      - Chronological correspondence, 1962 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 577-592)
      - Chronological correspondence, 1963-1966 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 593-610)
      - Chronological correspondence, January-April 1967 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 611-670)
      - Chronological correspondence, May-December 1967 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 671-738)
      - Chronological correspondence, 1968 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 739-795)
      - Chronological correspondence, 1971-1975 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 796-802)
      - Financial records including accounts of salaries and office expenses, 1952-1954 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 803-833)
      - Financial records including accounts of salaries and office expenses, 1955-1956 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 834-875)
      - Financial records including accounts of salaries and office expenses, 1957 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 876-933)
      - Financial records including accounts of salaries and office expenses, 1958-1960 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 934-1013)
      - Miscellaneous receipts, 1952-1959, (4 folders) (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 1014-1082)
      - Committee reports, 1952-1953, (oversized material housed in Box 37) (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 1083-1184)
      - Committee reports, 1954-1956 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 1185-1297)
      - Committee reports, 1957 (Box 12, Reel 5723, Frame 1298-1395)
      - Committee reports, 1957 (Box 12, Reel 5724, Frame 11-27)
      - Committee reports, January-July 1958 (Box 12, Reel 5724, Frame 28-144)
      - Committee reports, August 1958-1959 (Box 12, Reel 5724, Frame 145-200)
      - Blueprints, 1957 (Box 37, Reel 5724, Frame 201-230)
      - Notes and writings, including typescripts: "On Architecture and Aesthetics" "L'UNESCO: Future Mal Logée," "Plans for New UNESCO Buildings Completed" 1949, undated (Box 12, Reel 5724, Frame 231-268)
      - Rough sketches of building designs (Box 12, Reel 5724, Frame 269-297)
      - Photographs of architects, plans and drawings (Box 12, Reel 5724, Frame 298-391)
        (Breuer, Pier Luigi Nervi, Eero Saarinen, Hernan Vieco Benjamin Wermiel, and Bernard Zehrfuss at conferences and dinners)
      - Photographs of plans and model (Box 12, Reel 5724, Frame 392-404)
      - Photographs of construction (Box 12, Reel 5724, Frame 405-420)
        (includes photo of Breuer, Nervi, and Zehrfuss on a patio)
      - Contact sheet photographs of completed project, exterior and interior (Box 12, Reel 5724, Frame 421-438)
      - Photographs of completed project, exterior, (15 folders; oversized material housed in Box 37) (Box 12, Reel 5724, Frame 439-628)